Filippo Mameli

Cortona, Tuscany | +39 3493041822 filippomameli@outlook.com

Summary

Experienced **Data Engineer** with a Master's Degree in Data Science. Skilled in data engineering and machine learning techniques, able to create effective solutions. Collaborative team player driven by innovation and problem solving. Committed to using data strategically to improve processes and provide valuable insights.

Experience

Agile Lab | Fully Remote

Big Data Engineer | 09/2024 - Present

• Part of the enabling team for the <u>Witboost</u> product, managing and executing client integrations.

Data Reply | Fully Remote

Machine Learning Engineer | 05/2022 - 07/2024

- Developed predictive algorithms for fleet management, using **Databricks** and **AWS Glue**, resulting in improved performance and reduced maintenance costs.
- Managed an API development team, ensuring smooth collaboration and timely delivery.
- Managed a state-of-the-art Databricks data hub platform using Terraform, handling over 100 TB of data. Developed a
 feature store for other data scientist teams and utilities to streamline development processes.

Dbiz | Arezzo

Data Engineer | 06/2021 - 05/2022

- Skilled in creating **interactive dashboards** for corporate spend reporting, mastering data extraction, manipulation and scheduling.
- Proficient in designing and developing serverless Mobile/Web applications with AWS for efficient, scalable solutions.

NTT Data | Milan

Data Engineer | 06/2020 - 06/2021

- Skilled in developing and deploying **big data products** within a microservices architecture, processing 10 million messages per hour with Kafka using Scala/Java and Python.
- Experienced in orchestrating deployments with Openshift and Kubernetes for efficient containerization.
- Adept at managing **DevOps pipelines** with Jenkins to streamline deployment processes.

Education

University of Florence | Florence, Tuscany

Master's degree in Computer Science - Data Science | 04/2020

- Presented the thesis titled "A NoGAN approach for image and video restoration and compression artifact removal" at the ACM International Conference on Multimedia. Publication
- Provided guidance and assistance as a university tutor within the Department of Computer Science at the University of Florence.
- Graduated with a final grade of 110/110.

Skills

- Programming languages: Python, Java/Scala, JavaScript, a bit of Go, Elixir, Rust
- AI/Machine Learning: PyTorch, FastAI, MLFlow, Keras, Scikit-learn, NumPy, Matplotlib, Huggingface
- Big Data and Databases: Databricks, Spark, DBT, Kafka, Hadoop, SQL, MongoDB/DynamoDB, Akka, Pandas
- Web: Next.js, React, React-Native, GraphQL/REST, Amplify
- Tools: Git, Bash, Zsh, Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes/Openshift, Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook
- Cloud: AWS, Azure, GCP, Vercel

Miscellaneous

Certifications: Associate Cloud Engineer - Google Cloud; English First Certificate

Social: Linkedin; Github; Personal website

Hobbies: Photography; Music; Cinema; Tech; Gaming